When you step into the freelancing world,
عندما تخطو في عالم العمل الحر
you'll realize that it's very different from a full-time job.
سوف تدرك أنه مختلف كلية عن العمل في وظيفة بدوام كامل.
In a full-time job,
في وظيفة الدوام الكامل
things are pretty defined.
تكون الأمور محددة جيدًا.
Your job role is defined.
ويكون دورك محددًا جيدًا.
Your responsibilities are more or less articulated.
وتكون مسؤولياتك معرفة بشكل أو بآخر.
In a freelancing world,
أما عالم العمل الحر
it is an open field.
فهذا مجال مفتوح.
There are so many clients out there who need to get work done.
وفيه الكثير جدًا من العملاء الذين يحتاجون شخصًا لإنجاز أعمالهم.
But how to find them?
ولكن كيف تجدهم؟
Where are those clients?
وأين هم هؤلاء العملاء؟
What strategies to adopt to win a project from clients?
وما هي الاستراتيجيات التي من ممكن اتباعها للحصول على المشروعات منهم؟
How to work with them effectively?
وكيف تعمل لديهم بكفاءة؟
In this course, the intent is not only to help you with all of
الهدف من هذه الدورة التدريبية ليس فقط مساعدتك خلال
these changes in freelancing but also to bootstrap your freelancing carrier.
كل تلك التغيرات للعمل الحر، ولكن أيضًا في إطلاق مشوارك المهني كموظف حر.
For those of you who are just starting out a freelancing carrier,
لأولئك منكم الذين بدأوا للتو شركة عمل حر،
you will see that it might be hard to get your first few gigs since you do not
فسوف ترون أن نيل أعمالكم الأولى من الممكن أن يكون شيئًا صعبًا حيث أنكم لا تملكون
have much in your profile to show to other clients or testimonials from other clients.
الكثير على صفحاتكم الشخصية لإظهاره للعملاء وليس لديكم شهادات من عملاء آخرين.
We'll discuss how to break this deadlock,
سوف نناقش كيفية الخروج من هذه الدائرة المغلقة
bootstrap your freelancing carrier and sooner than later,
وإطلاق مشوارك المهني الحر، وكيف أنك عاجلًا أو آجلًا
be able to obtain a competitive freelancing profile,
سوف يصبح بمقدورك أن تحصل على صفحة شخصية تنافسية لعملك الحر
so it is not so difficult to get new clients.
حتى يكون من السهل أن تحصل على عملاء جدد.
The best part, all of this course is based on learnings from practical experience.
أفضل ما في الأمر هو أن هذه الدورة مبنية على الأشياء المستفادة من التجربة العملية.
You'll see yourself going through
وطوال مدة الدورة سوف تجد نفسك
many scenarios throughout the course that you might face in
داخل سيناريوهات عديدة من المحتمل لك مواجهتها
real life and will compel you to think on
في الحياة الواقعية والتي سوف تدفعك للتفكير في
how to deal with a variety of situations. All the best.
كيفية التعامل في مختلف المواقف. بالتوفيق.